George Marshall Papers
George Marshall Papers
1940s-1965
Marshall, George, plastics engineer.
1 legal-size box, 1 square tube
Collection contains correspondence from Wasco Chemical from 1959, photographs of plastics manufacturing facilities, plastics industry-related publications, and piping diagrams for a factory for Great American Plastics in Fitchburg, MA.
2651137
Biographical History
George Marshall worked in the plastics and chemical industries. He worked for the Leominster, Mass. office of Borden Chemical in 1955 and by 1959 had moved to Wasco Chemicals, first in Cambridge, Mass. and then in Sanford, Maine.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The George Marshall Papers consists of blueprints (piping diagrams for a factory for Great American Plastics in Fitchburg, MA), papers (correspondence from Wasco Chemical from 1959), photographs of plastics manufacturing facilities, and publications related to the plastics indutry.
Related Material
has numerous holdings in the areas of plastics and industrial design. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; Plastics; Marshall, George, plastics engineer -- Archives.; Borden Chemical.; Great American Plastics.; Wasco (firm); Plastics industry and trade.; Factories.; Factories -- Fires and fire prevention.; Piping.; Correspondence.; Photographs.; Plumbing plans.; Engineers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Transfer from National Plastics Center and Museum, 11/06/2008. Originally, gift of children of Dorothy and George Marshall.
Inventory
- Blueprints
  - Great American Plastics, Fitchburg, Massachusetts, 1964; piping diagrams, rolled; 20 items (Oversize 1)
- Papers
  - Wasco Calculator promotional material, 1959-1960 (Box 1)
  - Wasco Chemical Co. (Box 1)
  - Water bath casting, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1959-1960 (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Factories, late 1940s-?; factories (exteriors and interiors), factory fires, ruins of factories, and a tanker on railroad tracks; locations are largely unidentified, a few include Illinois (Mt. Pulaski and Illiapolis), Massachusetts, and possibly Maine.; 2 folders, 70 items (Box 1)
- Publications
  - Borden, Casco News, 1954-1956 (Box 1)
  - DuPont, Lucite Manual, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Imperial Chemical Industries, Perspex Corrugated Acrylic Sheet, 2d Edition, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Rohm and Haas, Perspex Design and Fabrication Data, 1949; 1961 (Box 1)